https://balasailingclub.wordpress.com/bala-sailing-club-data-privacy-policy/

GDPR 2016
1. About this Policy.
1.1 This policy explains when and why we collect personal information about our members
and instructors, how we use it and how we keep it secure and your rights in relation to it.
1.2 We may collect, use and store your personal data, as described in this Data Privacy
Policy and as described when we collect data from you.
1.3 We reserve the right to amend this Data Privacy Policy from time to time without prior
notice. You are advised to check our website (http://www.balasc.org.uk ) or our Club
noticeboard regularly for any amendments (but amendments will not be made
retrospectively).
1.4 We will always comply with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) when
dealing with your personal data. Further details on the GDPR can be found at the website
for the Information Commissioner ( http://www.ico.org.uk ). For the purposes of the GDPR, we
will be the “controller” of all personal data we hold about you.
2. Who are we?
2.1 We are Bala Sailing Club. We can be contacted at Bala sailing Club, Pont Mwnwgl-y-
Llyn, Y Bala LL23 7BS. (Secretary: secretary@balasc.org.uk ) Tel. 01678-520464
3. What information we collect and why.
3.1 General membership information;
Type of information
Purposes
Legal basis of processing
Member’s name, address,
telephone numbers, e-mail
address(es).
Managing the Member’s
membership of the Club.
Managing the duty roster.
Performing the Club’s
contract with the Member.
For the purposes of our
legitimate interests in
operating the Club.
The names and ages of the
Member’s dependants
Managing the Member’s
and their dependants’
membership of the Club
Performing the Club’s
contract with the Member.
Performing the Club’s
contract with the Member.
Gender
Provision of adequate
facilities for members.
Page 1 of 5
changing rooms and toilets)
for each gender.
Reporting information to the
RYA.
For the purposes of the
legitimate interests of the
RYA to maintain diversity
data required by Sports
Councils.
The Member’s name, boat
name and sail number
Managing race entries and
race results.
Sharing race results with
other clubs, class
associations, and the RYA,
and providing race results
to local and national media.
Allocating moorings and
compound spaces.
For the purposes of our
legitimate interests in holding
races for the benefit of
members of the Club.
For the purposes of our
legitimate interests in
promoting the Club.
pages and using in press
releases.
contacting us by e-mail or
letter.
Radio call signs
Collected for a rally and
shared between those
participating in the rally.
Creating and managing the
Club’s online Membership
Directory.
details to appear in the
Membership Directory.
Bank account details of the
member or other person
making payment to the Club
Managing the Member’s
and their dependants’
membership of the Club,
the provision of services
and events.
Performing Bala sailing
Club’s contract with the
Member.
Type of information
Purposes
Legal basis of processing
Page 2 of 5
3.2 Information collected for regattas, open meetings and other events.
Type of information
Purposes
Legal basis of processing
Competitor’s name,
address, telephone
numbers, e-mail
address(es) bank and
payment details.
Managing the Competitors
entry in the Regatta/Open
meeting or other event(s)
Performing the Club’s
contract with the
Competitor.
For the purposes of our
legitimate interests in
operating the Regatta/Open
meeting or other event(s).
The names, boat details and
race results.
Managing event results for
class members and
information on results.
Performing the Club’s
contract with the
Competitor.
For the purposes of our
legitimate interests in
operating the Regatta/Open
meeting or other event(s).
contract with the
Competitor.
Gender
Provision of adequate
facilities for Competitors.
suitable facilities (including
changing rooms and toilets)
for each gender.
The Competitor’s name
boat, name, home club and
sail number.
allocating moorings and
compound spaces.
For the purposes of our
legitimate interests in
operating the Regatta/Open
meeting or other event(s).
our legitimate interests in
operating the club.
Photos and videos of
Competitors and their boats.
Putting on the event, club
and class website and
social media pages and
using in press releases.
at any time by contacting us
by email or letter.
Page 3 of 5
4. How we protect your personal data.
4.1We will not transfer your personal data outside the EU or EEA without your consent.
4.2 We have implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational
security in order to protect personal data from loss, misuse, or unauthorised alteration or
destruction.
4.3 Please note however that where you are transmitting information to us over the
internet this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure.
4.4 For any payments which we take from you online we will use a recognised online
secure payment system.
4.5 We will notify you promptly in the event of any breach of your personal data which
might expose you to serious risk.
5. Who else has access to the information you provide us?
5.1 We will never sell your personal data. We will not share your personal data with any
third parties without your prior consent (which you are free to withhold) except where
required to do so by law or as set out in the table above.
6. How long do we keep your information?
6.1 We will hold your personal data on our systems for as long as you are a member of the
Club and for as long afterwards as is necessary to comply with our legal obligations. We
will review your personal data every year to establish whether we are still entitled to
process it. If we decide that we are not entitled to do so, we will stop processing your
personal data except that we will retain your personal data in an archived form in order to
be able to comply with future legal obligations e.g. compliance with tax requirements and
exemptions, and the establishment exercise or defence of legal claims.
6.2 We securely destroy all financial information once we have used it and no longer need
it.
7. Your rights
7.1 You have rights under the GDPR:
(a) to access your personal data
(b) to be provided with information about how your personal data is processed
(c) to have your personal data corrected
(d) to have your personal data erased in certain circumstances
Page 4 of 5
(e) to object to or restrict how your personal data is processed
(f) to have your personal data transferred to yourself or to another business in certain
circumstances.
7.2 You have the right to take any complaints about how we process your personal data to
the Information Commissioner:
https://ico.org.uk/concerns/
0303 123 1113.
Cheshire SK9 5AF
For more details, please address any questions, comments and requests regarding our
data processing practices to our Data Protection Manager,
dutyrosterbala@virginmedia.com
Page 5 of 5
Share this:TwitterFacebookLike this:Like Loading...
Bala SC Webcams. To update click image.
Next Members Social
Easter Saturday. Evening meal and live singer.
LAKEVIEW CAFE
New for 2019. Set within Bala Sailing Club. Open to visitors now. Offering a great range of meals to the public and to members. Click here for more info >
News Post Categories
Cat Fleet (6)
Members (5)
Race Reports (17)
Uncategorized (13)
Visitor Info (3)
Create your website at WordPress.comGet started
Privacy & Cookies: This site uses cookies. By continuing to use this website, you agree to their use.
To find out more, including how to control cookies, see here:
Cookie Policy
%d bloggers like this:
